CONSTANTIN IORDAN

SENIOR SOFTWARE CONSULTANT / ENGINEER

Brasov, Romania | costi.iordan@gmail.com | +40.723.60.8360 | www.constantiniordan.ro

SUMMARY

I love what I do - and I put my heart into every project I take on.

With 18 years of experience, I've built solutions that solve real-world problems in e-commerce, telecom, transportation, logistics, and tourism.

Clean, scalable, and thoughtfully designed software is my craft, and every project is an opportunity to make something that truly matters.

SKILLS

- Technical leadership
- Client communication
- Computer programming
- Software architecture
- Business analysis
- Mentoring
- E-commerce

- PHP
- MySQL and PostgreSQL
- Spryker (Certified Solution Architect)
- Laravel
- ElasticSearch
- Docker

- Javascript
- Typescript
- React
- Vue
- Angular
- HTML and CSS
- Accesibility

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior software consultant/engineer Contractor

Sep 2021 - Present

- Deliver multiple Spryker e-commerce projects in automotive, sports events, and wholesale food industries as part of international teams.
- Plan, design and implement custom functionalities on Spryker platform. This includes third
 parties integrations, performance optimizations, catalog customization, custom admin
 interfaces and custom storefront themes.
- Rewrite React frontend for internal support application from a legacy code base to a modern tech stack using the latest technologies: React 19, React Material UI. This resulten in a more maintainable application with 100% unit test coverage using Jest and Testing Library React.
- Mentored developers into Spryker and PHP development.
- Created custom e-commerce platform using Laravel designed to meet the specific needs of
 the business. It includes advanced search capabilities, inventory management, catalog
 management, and real-time performance optimization using modern caching strategies. The
 platform is built using a modular monolith architecture, allowing for easy scalability and
 maintainability.
- Created custom rental management system with booking functionality, inventory tracking, and custom pricing and discounts. Built with Laravel Filament for admin panel efficiency and a custom frontend with vanilla css and vanilla JavaScript for a seamless user experience and simplicity.

Technical Lead - Nagarro/Iquest Technologies

Jun 2017 - Sep 2021

- Leading a team of web developers in order to deliver high quality solutions and respecting the agreed timelines. Provide technical solutions for a complex set of requirements.
- Provide support to junior team members with per programming, code reviews and mentorship.
- · Hold technical interviews.
- Worked on e-commerce project building a b2b application with Spryker.
- Worked on portal application with Angular and .Net backed.

Senior software engineer - Iquest Technologies

Jun 2015 - Jun 2017

- Worked on e-commerce projects building frontend for SAP Hybris applications using jsp or html templates with pug template language. (Bootstrap, Jquery, Sass, Responsive web design, Accessibility and optimisation for slow networks).
- Worked on AngularJS application with .Net backend for banking industry.
- · Mentored junior team members

Software engineer - Iquest Technologies

Feb 2013 - Jun 2015

- Develop single page application with EnvoJs for US based startup.
- Create responsive html templates for ecommerce applications based on Photoshop designs.

Web developer - Freelance

2006 - Feb 2013

- Create and maintain a custom b2c e-commerce solution written in plain php with custom administration flows and interface. Integrate with shipping service (Self AWB from Fan Curier and custom forms generation for Romanian Post Office).
- Develop and mantain an b2b / b2c ecommerce solution based on CakePhp written from scratch based on a very specific set of requirements. Custom product management, custom order management with multiple sales agents, data export features, custom product attributes with filtering functionality.
- Create online selling functionalities for bicycle parts on a existing platform built wit PHP and Mysql. Manage customer orders and keep up to date product catalog.
- Create presentation websites for multiple local businesses.
- Create website for local sports event with online registration functionality.

EDUCATION

Bachelor degree at Transilvania University

2008 - 2012

Construction engineer

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Languages: English, Romanian.
- Certifications: Spryker Solution Architect.